genealogytoday.com 2018-08-17

# Privacy Statement for Genealogy Today

## Our Privacy Statement

_Last updated October 3, 2012_

The owners of this site are committed to protecting your privacy. We recognize that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This privacy statement explains data collection and use practices of **www.genealogytoday.com** , which is owned and operated by Genealogy Today LLC, 74 Forest Road, New Providence, New Jersey. We stand firmly behind this policy, and will never implement changes to make it less protective of any customer information collected. 

By accessing this site, you are consenting to the information collection and use practices described in this privacy statement. 

Between 2005 and 2011, Genealogy Today LLC was awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices was thoroughly reviewed annually by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. In 2011, the owners of Genealogy Today elected to withdraw from the annual TRUSTe review process. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please first contact Illya D'Addezio by using this form. 

### Collection of your Personal Information

In general, you can visit this site without telling us who you are and without giving any personal information about yourself. There are times, however, when we may need personal information from you to maintain the quality of our databases and to safeguard others visitors who may view the research information that you submit. 

We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you (personal information) or allows us to contact you to provide a service or carry out a transaction that you have requested such as receiving information about Genealogy Today products and services, entering a contest, ordering e-mail newsletters, or joining a limited-access premium site or service. 

The personal information we collect (that is not otherwise publicly available) may include your name, e-mail, phone, address, information about your interests and research experience, and credit card information. 

This site offers a Tell A Friend service for the purpose of allowing you to easily share our sites information (i.e. name, web site address) with other people who you know to be interested in genealogy. If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Genealogy Today LLC stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us by using this form to request that we remove this information from our database. 

This site offers a variety of query services. A query service allows you to post information to other visitors with the intention that they will contact you if they have knowledge of the person you are looking for. If you choose to use any of our query services (e.g. Family Tree Climbers, Missing Persons Register, First Name Basis), we will ask for your name and email address, along with details about the person you are trying to locate. The information you post will be visible to all Genealogy Today visitors. While not required, **we strongly recommend** that you join our free membership program, Team Roots, before using our query services. This will allow you to easily edit and withdraw any listings you create. 

This site offers several private research services (e.g. Ancestor Tracker). These services are for you to store and track the progress of your research project(s), and to make the use of our site (as well as other external sites) more efficient. This information is not shared with other visitors, and you are able to update/withdraw the information at any time using the appropriate menu options. 

This site may collect certain information about your visit, such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address through which you access the Internet; the date and time you access the site; the pages that you access while at the site and the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked directly to our site. This information is used to help improve the site, analyze trends, and administer the site. 

We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information. This most frequently occurs as a result of an acquisition. In these events, your personal information is immediately protected by this policy. 

### Collection by Third-Party Sites, Ad Servers, and Sponsors

This site may contain links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the other sites' privacy notices as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties. 

The _Network Advertising Initiative_ now offers an **[Opt Out of Behavioral Advertising](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)** service. 

### Use of your Personal Information

The personal information collected this site will be used to operate the site and to provide the service(s) or carry out the transaction(s) you have requested or authorized. 

The personal information collected will only be shared with third parties in the following ways listed in this privacy statement. 

In support of these uses, Genealogy Today may use personal information to provide you with more effective customer service, to improve the site, and to make the site easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information or by customizing the site to your particular preference or interests. 

Some of our services offer individuals the ability to publicly display certain personal information, such as a Team Roots member who wishes to publish research information as part of connecting with other members. The Team Roots member may adjust the privacy field in the Edit function to withdraw this information from public view at any time. Participation in such services is always optional. 

In some cases, such as The Marketplace, businesses use our services to sell products and services to you on our sites. When required to complete a sales transaction, we share the requisite personal information you have provided us with these third parties. 

We accept online payments through the **[PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/)** service, and use their shopping cart tools to allow our customers to combine multiple items into a single purchase. When you complete a purchase using Paypal, you are submitting your payment information to this company, and our access is limited to the information required to fullfil the order (e.g. name, address, products ordered). When using PayPal on our site, we DO NOT have access to your credit card information. Refer to their [privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside) for additional details. 

We also use a credit card processing company, **[Global Payments Inc.](http://www.globalpaymentsinc.com/)** , to bill you for goods and services ordered by mail. This company does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes. Refer to their [privacy policy](http://www.globalpaymentsinc.com/privacy.html) for additional details. 

We use an outside company, **[Everyone.net](http://www.everyone.net/)** , to offer our visitors free email accounts. When you register for an account you will be submitting your information to this company, and our access will be limited to your first, last and login names. Refer to their [privacy policy](http://www.everyone.net/main/html/p_policy.html) for additional details. 

The third parties mentioned above are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. 

In 2012, we entered into a co-marketing relationship with FindTheBest.com, Inc. for the development of the [Genealogy Database](http://genealogy-databases.genealogytoday.com/) and [Family Tree Software](http://familytreesoftware.genealogytoday.com/) comparison guides. The information and services provided within these sections of our website are written, hosted and managed by FindTheBest.com and are subject to [their privacy policy](http://www.findthebest.com/privacy). Any personal information collected by FindTheBest.com within these two sections (which may include email address, phone number and credit card data) is NOT shared with Genealogy Today. 

We support an affiliate program in conjunction with our marketplace, however, the affiliates are only permitted to view the order information (e.g. products and amounts charged) -- NOT the customer information. This information is presented to them in the form of summary reports. 

We also work closely with several affiliate businesses on special promotions. When we do this, we do not give that business your name and address. You may, however, be asked by these businesses to provide personal information in order to participate in the promotion. Please refer to the privacy policy of the affiliate business for details on how your personal information will be handled. 

We sometimes use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our site and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze site usage, as well as to offer you products, programs, or services. 

Genealogy Today LLC may disclose personal information if required to do so by law. We believe, in addition, it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or violations of our terms of use. 

### Control of your Personal Information

Except as otherwise described in this statement, personal information you provide on this site will not be shared outside of Genealogy Today. As described below in the next section, you can access your personal information and make choices about how you wish to be contacted. 

Please be aware that this privacy statement and any choices you make on the site will not necessarily apply to personal information you may have provided to Genealogy Today in the context of other, separately operated, products or services. 

### Access to your Personal Information

You can review, edit and remove the personal information and contact preferences you provided by visiting your Team Roots start page (login at <http://teamroots.com/> ). You will be asked to enter your userid and password before viewing your personal information. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. 

Non-members may join the free Team Roots program and have any personal information previously provided linked into your Team Roots profile. To have your information removed without joining, you may contact us by using this form. 

We also maintain a Do-Not-E-Mail Registry that gives users the option to not receive future communications from any of the sites owned by Genealogy Today LLC. To access this feature, visit http://www.genealogytoday.com/info/register.html . Submitting your information to this registry will not prevent this site from sending automatic confirmation emails triggered by features and services you utilize (e.g. make a purchase, subscribe to a database). 

### Security of your Personal Information

Genealogy Today is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. 

We limit access to personal information about you to employees and contractors who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. 

Highly sensitive personal information, (e.g. credit card information) is never stored on our public servers, and is only retained offline for 18 months following your most recent sales transaction at which time it is shredded and discarded. Of course, we transmit the credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing. 

Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Notice. 

### Use of Cookies

We use cookies on this site to ensure the integrity of the registration process and to personalize the site. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web server. This cookie is associated with your personal information only while you are logged into the Team Roots service. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of this or other Web sites you visit. 

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers, marketing partners) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by www.genealogytoday.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties. 

### Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

Our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.

### Changes to this Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage. 

### Contacting Genealogy Today LLC

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact us by using this form, calling 908-963-1277 Monday through Friday between the hours of 10am and 4pm EST, or writing to us at Genealogy Today LLC, P.O. Box 911, New Providence, NJ 07974-0911.
